# **SAMMY SAMKOUGH**

862-239-0100 | sammysamkough@gmail.com | Wayne, NJ 07470; New York City, NY 10001 https://sammy.pizza | https://github.com/ssamkough | https://linkedin.com/in/ssamkough

## WEB FRONT END ENGINEER; BILT REWARDS

## **SUMMARY:**

**Software Engineer with 5+ years of industry experience** building for the web, with strong problem solving skills. With great flexibility, an ability to be articulate, and incredible interpersonal skills, coding w/ TypeScript/JavaScript, React, Node.

Areas of Expertise: FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT // TESTABLE CODE // UX DESIGN

#### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:**

- Languages HTML; CSS; JavaScript; TypeScript; Python; C#; Java; SQL
- Frameworks React.js; Next.js; Remix; Astro.js; Gatsby.js; Svelte; Django; Node.js; Express.js; React Native
- Applications Git; Babel; Postgres; Firebase; GraphQL; Storybook; AWS; Google Cloud; Vercel; Chromatic

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

Bonny Systems, New York City, NY; Wayne, NJ

Oct 2023 - Present

Founding Engineer

- Achieving over 80% reduction in website load times by improving core web vitals which includes minimizing JavaScript usage, image optimization, and adherence to web standards.
- Partnering with design agencies to build and deploy modern websites / APIs with CI/CD pipelines using content management systems (CMS) like WordPress or advanced front-end frameworks such as Next.js and Astro.js.

Canal, San Francisco, CA; New York City, NY

May 2021 - Jul 2023

Software Engineer

- Developed the onboarding process to adapt to evolving user needs, coordinating constant QA sessions, utilizing React, Next.js, TypeScript, XState, Django and GraphQL which lead to an overall 40% increase in user satisfaction.
- Collaborated with a fast-moving design / product team of five to create in-house design system that replaced the Shopify Polaris design system which led to an increase of development speed by over 60%.
- Enhanced web app usability across all departments by 60% through leading targeted accessibility training and guidelines for the development team.
- Led the standardization of UI / UX component testing within the in-house design system, significantly reducing component-specific bugs by over 70% using Chromatic and Storybook.

Popstar, Remote USA

Nov 2020 - Apr 2021

Software Engineer

- Launched a feature-rich iOS application using Swift and Firebase / NoSQL, which offered an elegant vertical video experience, including social interactions such as sharing and commenting on videos.
- Integrated backend Firebase push notifications and cloud messaging enhancing user engagement by 80%.

Decusoft, Hybrid (Ramsey, NJ; Remote USA)

May 2019 - Oct 2020

Full Stack Software Developer

- Implemented table features like filtering and sorting algorithms using JavaScript, C# / ASP.NET and SQL.
- Optimized complex SQL queries which increased the load time performance of the main MySQL table by 50%.

## **EDUCATION:**